<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>
    <string name="app_name">YeastHelper</string>
    <string name="nav_header_title">Yeast calculator</string>
    <string name="menu_home">Yeast calculator</string>
    <string name="menu_gallery">Tips for baking</string>
    <string name="menu_slideshow">Holiday baking</string>
    <string name="menu_fach">Technical terms</string>
    <string name="menu_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="menu_spenden">Support us!</string>
    <string name="f.lass">Take your time</string>
    <string name="f.immer">Time and again you see so-called \"express recipes\" for baking bread on the internet. &#10;These promise fresh, homemade bread within a few hours - usually with the help of very large amounts of yeast. &#10;Of course, this can be useful if you want to bake fresh bread spontaneously and hardly have the time. &#10;However, if you bake more regularly and are interested in a much more intensive taste, I advise you to switch to the so-called \"long-term leavening\". &#10;For the optimal yeast quantity calculation of your favourite recipe, use this calculator.</string>
    <string name="f.jedes">Every loaf deserves to be &#10;baked!</string>
    <string name="f.nichts">" Don't rush things"</string>
    <string name="f.orga">" Get organised before baking"</string>
    <string name="f.ruck">Setbacks are part of the game - even when baking bread. &#10;Especially in the beginning, you will make many mistakes: accidentally using the wrong ingredients, wrong quantities or a classic overproofing. &#10;Often the dough looks like it should be thrown away. &#10;My advice to you: give the dough a chance and put it in the oven. &#10;Maybe the result will surprise you and you will discover a new favourite product.</string>
    <string name="f.dingen">As with so many things, no master has fallen from the sky. &#10;You should also be aware of this when choosing a recipe. &#10;Of course, recipes with an incredible number of ingredients sound incredibly exciting, but I still recommend starting with smaller recipes. &#10;Once you have a feel for different doughs and your basic recipes work, &#10;you can move on to more advanced recipes and inspire others with your knowledge.</string>
    <string name="f.vorfreude">Despite understandable anticipation of baking, structured preparation is sensible and necessary. &#10;Anyone who has ever noticed that an ingredient is missing while kneading by hand and then tried to get it out of the cupboard &#10;and weigh it with dough-smeared hands knows what I am talking about. &#10;So before you start baking, think about what you need and arrange it neatly on your work surface. &#10;If you are missing a material, get creative. &#10;For example, a pasta strainer with a kitchen towel inserted can be a great alternative to a proofing basket &#10;or you can use a flower sprayer to create steam in the oven.</string>
    <string name="f.teiglinge">" When will my dough or dough pieces be ready ?"</string>
    <string name="f.daumen">Especially at the beginning it is difficult to develop a feeling for the dough. How long do I have to knead my dough or how long does my dough have to rest? These are two questions I often asked myself at the beginning. There are simple tricks for this &#10;&#10; kneading time: For this you can take a piece of dough that is about the size of a walnut and hold it between your hands. &#10;Gently and sensitively pull the piece of dough apart with both hands so that a thin layer of dough forms. &#10;This layer of dough should be pulled so thin that light can shine through. If this thin layer of dough tears, the dough has not been kneaded enough. &#10;&#10;Proofing time: For this \"problem\" there is the so-called thumb test. &#10;Press a slight notch into your dough with your thumb. &#10;If the notch springs right back, the dough is not quite ready. &#10;If the notch does not return to its original shape, the dough has been proofing too long. &#10;For optimal proofing time, the notch springs back slightly, but not to the 100% original shape.</string>
    <string name="s.einwaagen">" No scales for the weights"</string>
    <string name="s.mehl">Weighing out flour without scales</string>
    <string name="s.Mehlvolumen">Flour volume</string>
    <string name="s.Durchmesser">Diameter</string>
    <string name="s.Gramm">Gram</string>
    <string name="s.Hefe">Weighing yeast without scales</string>
    <string name="s.Knetmaschine">" Kneading without a kneading machine"</string>
    <string name="s.Arbeitsfläche">Kneading with work surface</string>
    <string name="s.ohneArbeitsflaeche">Kneading without a work surface</string>
    <string name="s.Überschrift">Holiday baking</string>
    <string name="s.BBQ">Who hasn\'t experienced it: You go on holiday and want to make a flatbread to go with the BBQ. &#10;Unfortunately, your holiday home has neither a scale nor a kneading machine. &#10;There are various solutions to these problems.</string>
    <string name="s.go">Go</string>
    <string name="s.mehlwaage">To measure the flour without scales, there is a simple solution: &#10;You use the bulk density of flour. &#10;The bulk density indicates how heavy a substance is in relation to a certain volume. Water, as an example, has a bulk density of 1, which means that 1000 ml of water weighs 1 kg. &#10;Flour, on the other hand, is lighter than water. So 1000 ml of flour weighs only about 500-600g. Now you can use a container - preferably with a calibration mark - to weigh the flour. &#10;Enter the ml number into the calculator and the number of grams will be calculated.</string>
    <string name="s.Hefewaage">To measure a quantity of yeast without a scale, you can simply form your fresh yeast into a ball. &#10;Depending on the diameter of the yeast ball, the weight of the yeast can be estimated. &#10;Simply measure the size (millimetres) of the ball with the ruler on the screen and enter the value into the calculator. &#10;The amount of yeast will be given to you in grams. Of course, these are not absolutely exact values, &#10;but it will be enough for your holidays and your spontaneous baking desire.</string>
    <string name="s.Schüssel">If you do not have space for kneading, use a bowl and a wooden spoon. &#10;This variant is based on the lift kneader used in industry. &#10;You mix all the ingredients in a bowl and mix them by hand or with a wooden spoon. &#10;In the second step, you place your mixer at one end of the bowl and pull the dough to the middle of the bowl. Then turn the bowl a few centimetres, start again at the edge and pull the dough to the middle of the bowl. &#10;Repeat this process until your dough stretches well without tearing.</string>
    <string name="s.Arbeitsflaeche">If you have a work surface for kneading, you can use this variant. &#10;There you also mix all the ingredients at the beginning. You can also use a bowl or directly your work surface for this. &#10;This method is based on a sprial kneader, which creates a force effect from top to bottom. &#10;To do this, you reach under the dough with your hand and fold it over itself. Then press the folded piece of dough into the dough from top to bottom. &#10;After this step, the bowl is turned a few centimetres and the kneading process starts again: You reach under the dough, fold it over itself and press the folded piece into the rest of the dough.</string>
    <string name="s.Kneter">To make dough without a kneader, you can use the efficiency of industrial kneaders as a guide&#10;For holidays, two methods are suitable, which differ in whether you have a worktop available for kneading or not&#10;With both methods, it should be noted that the kneading time is longer than with a machine. To estimate approximately when your dough has been kneaded long enough, there is the so-called window test. &#10;(see -Tips- When is my dough or my dough pieces ready?)</string>
    <string name="h.Hefeberechnung">Yeast calculation</string>
    <string name="h.Mehlgewicht">Flour weight</string>
    <string name="h.inGramm">in gram</string>
    <string name="h.Teigruhe">Dough rest(h:min)</string>
    <string name="h.h">h</string>
    <string name="h.min">min</string>
    <string name="h.Temperatur">Temperature in °C</string>
    <string name="h.C">in °C</string>
    <string name="h.berechnen">Calculate</string>
    <string name="h.frischhefe">Fresh yeast in g</string>
    <string name="h.oder">or</string>
    <string name="h.Trockenhefe">Dry yeast in g</string>
    <string name="h.Sauerteihg">Sourdough in g</string>
    <string name="h.Teigruhebeendet">Dough rest is finished at:</string>
    <string name="e.Uschrift">Settings</string>
    <string name="Frage">\?</string>
    <string name="w.Fachbegriffe">Technical terms</string>
    <string name="w.Woerter">Especially at the beginning, you will come across many foreign words that you don\'t know yet. To help you get started, I\'ll list the terms that are most important to me and explain them to you.</string>
    <string name="w.Stockgare">" bulk fermentation"</string>
    <string name="w.vordemformen">Rest the dough after kneading but before shaping.</string>
    <string name="w.Stueckgare">Piece fermentation:</string>
    <string name="w.vordembacken">The resting time after shaping the dough but before baking.</string>
    <string name="w.Schwaden">Swaths:</string>
    <string name="w.krumenbild">Steam is the water vapour that is added to the baking process. It ensures a better crust appearance.</string>
    <string name="w.Teigausbeute">Dough yield:</string>
    <string name="w.TAerklaert">The dough yield (TA) indicates how many kilograms of water are used per 100 kilograms of flour. The higher the TA, the more water is used. &#10;But please note: The higher the TA, the more difficult it is to process. &#10;As an example: 500 grams of flour and 300 grams of water are used in the recipe. &#10;The result is a dough yield of 160.</string>
    <string name="w.Hydration">Hydration:</string>
    <string name="w.hydrationerklaaert">Hydration is the same as TA, but is expressed as a percentage. The percentage of water is calculated in relation to the flour. &#10;As an example: 500 grams of flour and 300 grams of water are used in the recipe. &#10;The result is a hydration of 60 %.</string>
    <string name="w.griffigkeit">Grip:</string>
    <string name="w.griffigekiterklaert">Grip describes the structure of the flour. If a flour with a high grip is required, this means a dark flour with a high proportion of husks.</string>
    <string name="w.type">Type:</string>
    <string name="w.typerklaert">The type indicates how many milligrams of minerals are contained in 100 grams of flour. &#10;Since the minerals are located in the outer part of the grain, the type increases the darker the flour becomes.</string>
    <string name="w.Schluss">Conclusion:</string>
    <string name="w.schlusserklaert">When a ball of dough is formed into a shape, there is a seam. This is called the end.</string>
    <string name="w.Wirken">Work:</string>
    <string name="w.synonym">Used as a synonym for shaping the dough.</string>
    <string name="w.ausbund">Ausbund:</string>
    <string name="w.ausbunderklaert">The torn part of the crust, which is formed during the baking process, is called the collar. This can be caused by a cut or by accident.</string>
    <string name="settings.Entwickler">The developers introduce themselves:</string>
    <string name="settings.michi">Michi</string>
    <string name="settings.sebi">Sebi</string>
    <string name="VorstellungMichi">My name is Michael. My professional journey began with an apprenticeship as a food technology specialist. Even then, it was clear to me that I wanted to combine my passion for food and technology to develop innovative products and advance the food industry. In the following two years, I was allowed to work in the quality department and thus gained a deep insight into the processes and standards that are essential for the production of high-quality and safe food. After my apprenticeship, I continued my education and graduated as a technician in food technology. Now I am about to start a new chapter in my career: soon I will begin a degree in biochemistry. I am very much looking forward to this challenge as it will allow me to broaden and deepen my knowledge to delve even deeper into the scientific aspects of food development. Away from my professional career, football and music club are my great passions. In football, I not only have the opportunity to be active in sports, but also to work in a team and achieve goals together. In my free time, I am always open to new experiences. I enjoy going on hikes to enjoy nature and also like to try my hand in the kitchen to create new recipes.</string>
    <string name="VorstelungSebi">My name is Sebi and I am happy to introduce myself to you. My path began with my A-levels at the Technical High School, where I discovered my enthusiasm for technology and innovation. This was followed by my studies in computer science, which introduced me to the fascinating world of programming and digital technologies.  During my studies, I developed a particular passion for the field of autonomous driving. The idea of having vehicles navigate autonomously with the help of artificial intelligence and advanced algorithms fascinates me immensely. It is an area that is constantly growing and will have a significant impact on the future of mobility.  Besides my professional career, I am an avid mountain biker. Exploring nature and experiencing the thrill of off-road riding gives me the time out I need from the hustle and bustle of everyday life. It helps me clear my head and recharge my batteries to engage in my projects and challenges.</string>
    <string name="h.sinn">This calculator is designed to help you find the optimal amount of yeast for your recipe. This can be useful if, for example, you find a recipe that you want to bake but are unhappy with the given resting time for the dough or if you prefer to store the dough in the fridge instead of at room temperature. To do this, add up the flour used in the recipe (regardless of the type of flour) and enter it under flour weight. Then think about how long you want to let your dough rest - enter the hours and minutes in the corresponding field. In the last field, enter the temperature at which the dough should rest. After you have entered all three things, click on -Calculate-. The required amounts of fresh yeast, dry yeast or sourdough are then calculated in grams.</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="spenden.unterstuetzen">How can you support us?</string>
    <string name="spenden.arten">You can support us in three different ways. You have the option to buy a delicious digital fortune biscuit for only 1€ and then receive a future reading directly after the purchase. But don\'t worry, the app of course remains free in any form and can be used without donations without any restrictions. If you don\'t want to spend money on this biscuit, you can click the button for the -free- fortune biscuit instead. All you have to do is watch a short promotional video in its entirety and you will immediately receive your fortune reading without having to pay anything. And if you don\'t like a fortune biscuit or a future reading, there is still another way you can support us. You can use the button on our Ko-Fi page to leave a contribution for our coffee fund if you like. But again, the use of the app remains free of charge and without any restrictions. Your help is greatly appreciated in any form, and we thank you for your support!</string>
    <string name="spenden.keks">Fortune biscuit for 1€</string>
    <string name="spenden.Kaffeekasse">Coffee fund</string>
    <string name="spenden.kostenloser">free fortune biscuit</string>
    <string name="spenden.buttonKeks">Fortune biscuit</string>
    <string name="spenden.txtkeks">With this button you can buy a delicious digital fortune biscuit for only 1€ and receive your personal future reading afterwards. The fortune biscuit not only brings joy, but also gives you an insight into your future!  Please note that the fortune biscuit is purchased with real money.</string>
    <string name="spenden.txtkostenkeks">With this special button you get a free fortune biscuit. It\'s very simple: press the button, watch the short commercial that pops up, and after you close the commercial, you\'ll immediately get the interpretation of your future. The best part is that this version of the biscuit is completely free for you! At the same time, it\'s a meaningful opportunity for us, as the ad revenue allows us to further improve the app so you can enjoy and benefit from it even more. So what are you waiting for? Get your free fortune biscuit and receive an exciting reading of the future!</string>
    <string name="spenden.GeldfürunsereKaffeekasse">Money for our coffee fund</string>
    <string name="spenden.txtKaffekasse">If you click on this button, you will be taken directly to our Ko-Fi page. There you have the possibility to give us a freely selectable amount into our coffee fund with the payment method of your choice. With this money we can buy our elixir of life, coffee, and also work on improvements for the app at night.  Because as the saying goes: -Believe in miracles, love and above all coffee.    Your support is a huge help to us in making the app even better and more user-friendly. We are incredibly grateful for every contribution that enables us to continue our passion for this app and constantly improve it.  So, if you\'d like to support us and give us a cup of coffee, we\'d love any contribution you can give.  Of course, it is important for me to point out that you should not spend your last money on this app. If you are already struggling to scrape together money for important expenses like rent, just enjoy this wonderful free app and keep your money for the things that really matter to you.  Your satisfaction and well-being are very important to us and we don\'t want you to burden yourself financially in any way. The use of the app remains completely free and unlimited, so you can enjoy it at any time without any worries.</string>
    <string name="Spracheaendern">In which language do you want to display the app?</string>
    <string name="Code1">Today is your lucky day. Proceed with courage!</string>
    <string name="Code2">You will soon experience an unexpected joy.</string>
    <string name="Code3">Believe in yourself, for you are more capable than you think.</string>
    <string name="Code4">The best things in life are still on their way to you.</string>
    <string name="Code5">Be patient, good things take time.</string>
    <string name="Code6">Your creativity will lead you to great successes.</string>
    <string name="Code7">Today is a day full of positive surprises.</string>
    <string name="Code8">A smile can do wonders, try it out.</string>
    <string name="Code9">Good things come to those who wait.</string>
    <string name="Code10">Your perseverance will pay off, keep at it!</string>
    <string name="Code11">Be open to new opportunities; they might surprise you.</string>
    <string name="Code12">You have the ability to overcome obstacles.</string>
    <string name="Code13">Todays difficulties will be tomorrow\'s memories.</string>
    <string name="Code14">Believe in yourself, and others will too.</string>
    <string name="Code15">Your intuition will guide you in the right direction.</string>
    <string name="Code16">Set clear goals and pursue them persistently.</string>
    <string name="Code17">You will soon receive a special opportunity.</string>
    <string name="Code18">Look out for the small joys in life.</string>
    <string name="Code19">Luck comes to those who think positively.</string>
    <string name="Code20">Your perseverance will lead you to your destination.</string>
    <string name="Code21">Leave the past behind and focus on the future.</string>
    <string name="Code22">Trust your instincts; they will guide you.</string>
    <string name="Code23">You will benefit from the support of your friends.</string>
    <string name="Code24">Today is a good day to take a risk.</string>
    <string name="Code25">You have the power to make your dreams come true.</string>
    <string name="Code26">Treat others the way you want to be treated.</string>
    <string name="Code27">Your resourcefulness will be admired.</string>
    <string name="Code28">Today is a day to be grateful for what you have.</string>
    <string name="Code29">The solution to your problem is already within you.</string>
    <string name="Code30">There is always a reason to smile, find yours!</string>
    <string name="Code31">The best time for a fresh start is now.</string>
    <string name="Code32">Believe in the magic of beginnings; anything is possible.</string>
    <string name="Code33">Your talents will soon be recognized.</string>
    <string name="Code34">Celebrate the small progress you make.</string>
    <string name="Code35">Hold on to your dreams; they are worth it.</string>
    <string name="Code36">Your kindness will bring joy to others.</string>
    <string name="Code37">The world is waiting to be discovered by you.</string>
    <string name="Code38">Trust in your ability to overcome obstacles.</string>
    <string name="Code39">You are unique; show the world your individuality.</string>
    <string name="Code40">Today is a day to help other people.</string>
    <string name="rechner.beschreibung">Welcome to our handy recipe converter! With this smart tool you can easily convert the quantities of an existing recipe. Whether you\'ve found a recipe for a delicious loaf of bread but want to make two, or you just want to make a smaller portion, this calculator makes it easy!  Imagine you\'ve found a fantastic recipe that makes your mouth water. But then the moment comes when you realise that the quantities are only for one portion. Don\'t worry, with our recipe converter this is no longer a problem!  You no longer have to calculate all the ingredients twice in your head or laboriously convert them. All you have to do is enter the ingredient quantities in the form and select the desired multiplier. If you want to prepare twice the amount, simply choose a multiplier of 2. And if you only want to make half the recipe, choose a multiplier of 0.5. Of course, you can also choose other factors.</string>
    <string name="rechner.Rezeptrechner">Recipe calculator</string>
    <string name="Zutat1">Ingredient 1</string>
    <string name="zutat2">Ingredient 2</string>
    <string name="zutat3">Ingredient 3</string>
    <string name="zutat4">Ingredient 4</string>
    <string name="zutat5">Ingredient 5</string>
    <string name="zutat6">Ingredient 6</string>
    <string name="Multiplikator">Multiplier</string>
    <string name="Rezeptrechner">Recipe calculator</string>


</resources>